Peter J Boyle

5828 Pisgah Way, Charlotte, NC 28217 973-650-0479 Boyle.Peter614@gmail.com

SUMMARY

Dedicated EMT-Paramedic with experience in both individual and team based medicine. Well trained in clinical and field care settings, having begun as a Navy Hospital Corpsman, and progressed into civilian medicine as an EMT and EMT-Paramedic. Currently recovering from an illness and ready to continue in a new setting with new challenges.

QUALIFICATIONS

- Innovative
- Experienced
- Loyal and hard working
- Function well in team environments
- Tactical Decision Making

EXPERIENCE

10/2020-1/2021

• UNCC Coding Bootcamp- Studied in a full time immersive full stack web development program utilizing languages such as HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Javascript, ¡Query, Node.js, Express.js, and React.

03/2019-Current

 Dealing with a serious illness and being repeatedly hospitalized I was unable to continue working. Now diagnosed, treated, and stable, I am ready and excited to move on.

08/2017-03/2019- Fort Mill Rescue

• Lead Paramedic serving ALS 911 calls

01/2017-8/2017- Century Ambulance

- Lead Paramedic serving ALS transport, 911 calls, and serving as a driver for BLS transports
- Certified on ventilator, pediatric, and advanced cardiac calls

08/2016-12/2016- Paramedic- Liberty Ambulance Service

- Lead paramedic on a shift based vehicle involved in both BLS and ALS transport and care
- Responsible for transport of critical patients including those needing ventilator and cardiac monitoring Paramedic student (FSCJ North Campus)
 - More than 600 clinical hours with Jacksonville Fire Rescue and UFHealth Jacksonville ED and Trauma

 Center
- Certifications include EMT, BLS, ACLS, PHTLS, AMLS, PEPP, FL EMT-P, NREMT-P, SC EMT-P 1/2014-8/1/16- UFHealth Jacksonville Surgery
 - Responsible for evaluation and treatment plans of both surgical and non-operative patients within the surgical suite
 - Specialize in traumatic and orthopedic patients who require immediate diagnosis and treatment

• Comfortable working for multiple providers in a fast paced environment while maintaining standards of care already established within UFHealth

Military Experience- 2008-2012

- As the sole medical provider for a reconnaissance and surveillance platoon, functioned as both a team member, as well as a medical asset
- Created long standing medical standard operating procedures including medevac procedures and techniques for extrication and movement still in practice
- Trained in both reconnaissance and surveillance as well as direct action and target acquisition
- Medical courses including: Cold Weather and Mountain Medicine, Diving Medicine for Medical Professionals (ARC), Trauma Life Support, Live Tissue and Tactical Combat Casualty Care (Instructor)

Other Work Experience

- 2012-2013- Team Medic- Ronin Security- Responsible for team medical care within a personal security detail employed by a high visibility political family
- 2014-2015- Dock Unloading Supervisor- Responsible for a team of dock workers in care of several multi thousand dollar shipments per day for both Home Depot and Target